ZHOUYINGCHENG LIAO(廖周应成)

CONTACT INFORMATION

Address 800 Dongchuan Rd, E-mail patrickliao2007@gmail.com

Shanghai, 200240, China Homepage zycliao.github.io

Mobile Phone (+86) 15821183231

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in the area of computer vision, deep learning. I did research on object detection and face recognization before. Currently, I am working on human skin mesh reconstruction which could be combined with pose estimation.

EDUCATION

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Sep, 2015 - Present

Undergraduate Student

- · Major: Information security
- \cdot School of Eletronic Information and Electrical Engineering

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Apr, 2017 - June, 2018

Undergraduate Researcher

- · Advisor: Prof. Bingbing Ni
- · Face recognition, face detection
- · Object detection
- · Self-supervised learning

SenseTime Research

July, 2018 - Present

Research Intern

- · Pose estimation
- · Human skin mesh reconstruction

PUBLICATIONS

Uniface: A Unified Network for Face Detection and Recognition
Accepted by the 24th International Conference on Pattern Recognition. ICPR 2018

[paper][poster]

· Zhouyingcheng Liao, Peng Zhou, Tailong Wu and Bingbing Ni

- · A bottom-up/top-down structure is adopted to combine face detection and recognization
- · An attention mechanism is adopted to replace face alignment
- · A single-network model, i.e. Uniface network is proposed which achieves the accuracy of 99.0% on LFW

Live Face Verification with Multiple Instantialized Local Homographic Parameterization [paper]

Accepted by the 27th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence. IJCAI 2018

- · Chen Lin, **Zhouyingcheng Liao**, Peng Zhou, Jianguo Hu and Bingbing Ni
- · A model which could classify live facial sequence and recorded facial sequence is proposed
- · Due to local homography property of recorded facial sequence, a transformation network is embedded in the model
- · Each image is divided into several patches and multiple instance learning is applied

UNDER-REVIEW PAPERS

Learning to Fuse - A Noise Prediction Framework for Denoising Monte Carlo Rendering Images

Submitted to Pacific Graphics 2018

- · Zhouyingcheng Liao*, Yiheng Zhang* and Lizhuang Ma (* denotes equal contribution)
- · A smoothing network that predicts pixel-wise denoising kernels
- · A sharpening network that directly predicts each denoised pixel
- \cdot A mask network that learns to fuse above two outputs to form the final output

AWARDS

MCM/ICM 2017 Problem E Meritorious Winner

Feb, 2017

· Zhouyingcheng Liao, Ziping Liu and Qiucheng Wu, Advisor: Fan Wu

31st Chinese Physics Olympiad (Jiangxi Province) First Prize

Sep, 2014

· Rank: 21^{st}

SKILLS

Programming Python
Language C/C++

HTML/CSS

Verilog

Deep learning TensorFlow framework MxNet

PyTorch